准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
新闻智能
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
醒醒  小蜗
Wake up, Gary
现在要来看
It's time for
裤头村新闻  主持人是帕奇帕金斯
Bikini Bottom News with Perch Perkins
海胆哥与败蜗子秀
有道理  小蜗
Good thinking, Gary
新闻可能会颠三倒四
The news can be pretty topsy-turvy
裤头村
新闻
晚上好  裤头村
Good evening, Bikini Bottom
下面是今晚要闻
In tonight's top story
本地一只松鼠受困井中
a local squirrel got stuck in a well
救命
Help
救我出来啊
Get me outta here, y'all
不管那位是谁都一定很尴尬
Must be embarrassing for whoever that is
但今天起先  机械智能发生了巨变
But first, radical changes in machine intelligence
were made today
正好这时候有只本地松鼠困在了井里
when a local squirrel got stuck in a well
看来再也用不着这些懒鬼消防员了
Looks like we won't be needing
those lazy firemen anymore
最新消息
This just in
本地电视台新闻记者帕奇帕金斯
Local TV news reporter Perch Perkins
已被开除
has been fired
开除了
Fired?
长期从事本地新闻工作的资深人士
The long-time local news veteran
即将被最新的新闻报道科技
is being replaced
by the latest in reporting technology
新闻机2000
Newsbot 2000
立刻替代
effective immediately
没错
Yes
谢谢  帕奇
Thank you, Perch
不能这么对我
You can't do this to me
我们在裤头村新闻
We here at Bikini Bottom News
致敬你长年以来为大众的服务
salute you for your years of service
抱歉  先生
Sorry, sir
不能让你带走任何公司财物
We can't let you leave with any company property
不能最起码留着盒子吗
Can't I at least keep the box?
可以留的
Of course
但是头发归演播室
But the hair belongs to the studio
那不是假发
That wasn't a toupee
太可怕了
This is terrible
一个机器不可能替代帕奇这样的人
A robot could never replace someone like Perch
在我们心中的地位
in our hearts
我不能坐视不管
I won't stand for this
得去给那家新闻演播室
I'm gonna give that news studio
一点颜色瞧瞧
a piece of my mind
头 脑
我们要帕奇
We want Perch
让帕奇回归
Bring back Perch
不好意思  先生
Pardon me, sir
可否跟各位观众详细介绍一下
Would you care to tell the folks back home more
你的抗议内容
about your protest?
好啊
Of course
帕奇帕金斯可是我全海洋最爱的记者
You see, Perch Perkins is my favorite newsman
in the whole ocean
而且
and--
等一下
Wait a second
帕奇
Perch?
是你吗
Is that you?
禁止逗留
No loitering
你身为帕奇帕金斯的粉丝
As a fan of Perch Perkins
如何评价机器人接替他职位一事
what do you think about a robot taking his job?
机器绝对不能拿来替代人
You can't just replace someone with a machine
派大机  代我抗议
Pat-tron, take over this protest for me
帕奇
Perch
回来啊
Come back
我们需要你
We need you
不会吧
Oh, no
老记者巷
Old Reporters Row
电视台的记者全在这度过停播时光
Where TV reporters finish out their off-air years
最低温度55度
Low of 55
最高温度72度
High of 72
本次要闻有
Our top stories--
交还给你  鲍勃
Back to you, Bob
帕奇
Perch
你不属于这里
You don't belong here
你还信任你的早餐麦片吗
Do you trust your breakfast cereal?
海神王的皇冠是否太小了
Is King Neptune's crown too small?
究竟是支持还是反对生育
Babies: for or against?
下面是急报
Here's a burning story
烧
该记者的旧报纸库存即将耗尽
This reporter's stash of old magazines is running low
帕奇
Perch?
谢天谢地
Thank goodness
得帮你脱离这里才行
We have to get you outta here
何苦呢
Why bother?
我就只会握着话筒
The only thing I know how to do is hold a microphone
何况新闻机全代我办好了
And Newsbot has that all sewn up
杂志
还有谁能雇用我呢
Who else would hire me?
有很多地方都能让你发挥自己的才能
There's lots of places
that can use a fish of your talents
来吧
Come on
我带你去看
I'll show ya
便宜货超市
Barg'n-Mart?
咱这应该是很需要找个员工
I suppose we could use someone
广播店内公告
to make in-store announcements
欢迎加入
Welcome aboard
请注意  便宜货超市的顾客们
Attention, Barg'n-Mart shoppers
乳制品区的奶酪正在特价
Cheese is on sale in the dairy aisle
花卉区的鲜花有超值优惠
And fresh flowers are marked down
in the floral department
花卉
帕奇帕金斯
Perch Perkins
七号通道新闻
Aisle Seven News
可否说说看这里发生了什么
Can you tell us what happened here?
帕奇
Well, Perch
我本来在买腌椰菜
I was procuring my pickles
突然我的掌心就湿了起来
when I noticed my palms had grown quite dewy
等我发现  却已经来不及了
Alas, my realization came too late
我的双手过度劳累  变得滑腻不堪
My hands, slickened from exertion
根本就扶不住美味的腌椰菜
could not hold on to their briny bounty
这则故事分外揪心
A heart-wrenching tale
帕金斯
Perkins
你应该通知保洁过来清理
You're supposed to call for a clean up
不是采访捣乱的
Not interview the mess maker
看看这些客人伤成什么样了
Look at all these injured customers
便宜货超市
我的腿被腌了
My pickled leg
你被开除了
You're fired
帕奇
Perch
没事
That's okay
我还给你安排了一样工作
I lined up another job for ya
蟹堡王
幸好我在这边有熟人
Luckily, I know a guy here
帕奇
Perch
欢迎光临蟹堡王
Welcome to the Krusty Krab
能有过气明星加入团队还挺不错
Always good to have a former celebrity on the team
谢谢
Thank you?
海绵宝宝说你很会用话筒
SpongeBob said you're good on the microphone
所以我要让你负责管得来速
So, I'm putting you on drive-through duty
好些年没用过了
Haven't used it in a couple of years
好
Okay
开始给我赚钱吧
Start making me some money
拉里我想要点
Larry wants to order
一份蟹黄堡
a Krabby Patty
要配薯条吗
Would you like fries with that?
好啊
Sure
当然行
Why not?
你想要升级到蟹黄堡套餐
Would you like to upgrade to a Krabby Combo
并且再来一份小份汽水吗
and get a small soda?
好吧
Okay?
你是否愿意说明为什么你的健身房
Would you like to explain why your gym
本月已连续违反15次健康法规
has been hit with 15 health code violations this month?
拉里我很忙的
Larry's a busy lobster, you know
直言不讳的几小时后
拉里我只是想要健身
Larry just wanted to work out
根本无意要害那些想健身的人
He didn't mean for all those people
to get athlete's shell
帕金斯
Perkins
我猜猜看
Let me guess
你要开除我吗
You're firing me?
下面是抢先报道  对
Here's the scoop: Yes
帕金斯  你要去哪
Perch, where are you going?
回到老记者巷  我只属于那里
Back to Old Reporter Row where I belong
不行
Oh, no
还不能放弃
We're not giving up yet
要是你别的东西全都不擅长
If you're no good at anything else
那你就只能再次报道新闻才行
then you'll just have to report the news again
可是要怎么办
But how?
放心
Don't you worry
我自有办法
I've got a plan
拜托让帕金斯回归吧
Please take Perch back
非带不可
You have to
我是这家新闻频道的经理
As the manager of this news network
给我解释一下为什么得带他回来
give me one good reason why I should
因为帕奇帕金斯的报道的新闻
Because Perch Perkins can out-report
能做到比你家破烂新闻机多
your dumb old Newsbot
随时随地都可以
anytime, anywhere
我想看他试试
I'd like to see him try
好
Good
那你就看吧
Then you will
海绵宝宝  我的报道没法比他多
SpongeBob, I can't out-report him
他做事可机械了
The guy's a machine
就是个机器
Literally
我相信你  帕奇帕金斯
I believe in you, Perch Perkins
好吧
Okay
比就比
It is on
新闻赛开打
It's a news-off
新闻赛
你们知道规矩
You know the rules
谁能限时报道最多新闻
Whoever reports the most news in the time allowed
谁就赢
wins
各就各位
On your mark
预备
Get set
新闻
News
巨型海牛
The huge manatee
今日一简单的新闻赛
A simple news-off
竟变得一发不可收拾  当时
turned ugly today when--
突发新闻
Breaking news
一场连环船祸
A pile-up has left
令多艘船受损至无法辨识
multiple boats mangled beyond recognition
最新消息
This just in
裤头村市中心一高层建筑严重起火
A towering inferno in downtown Bikini Bottom
新闻快报
News flash
一场海啸直冲城市而来
A tidal wave is headed straight for the city
本记者正在独家专访
And this reporter has an exclusive interview
海啸先生  你为什么要这么做
Mr. Wave, why are you doing this?
商务工业
该让新闻更上一层楼了
Time to turn the news up a notch
裤头村街道出现大量凹坑
Bikini Bottom streets pocked with potholes
抢先
Scoop
究竟是谁一直在把老太太们打倒在地
Who keeps tipping over our old ladies?
快报
News flash
通向贝壳城的大桥倒塌了
The bridge to Shell City has collapsed
我的腿
My leg
独家
Exclusive
根本就不可能有谁能报道那么多新闻
There's no way anyone could report that much news
除非
Unless
快来  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
神秘皮疹席卷海滩游客
Mysterious rash covers beach goers
第一航海银行
裤头村银行遭劫
Bikini Bottom bank robbed
蟹暴亡
蟹老板垃圾
本地快餐店遭到毁坏
Vandals strike local fast food restaurant
我们中断这一大堆的新闻
We interrupt this onslaught of news
插播一则特别报道
to bring you a special report
特别报道
本地新闻机器人  新闻机
Local news robot, Newsbot
所报道的新闻均为他所致
has been causing the very stories he reports on
他炸毁了大桥
He destroys the bridges
抢劫了银行
He robs the banks
还把老太太打倒在地
He tips over the old ladies
而现在  他正在毁坏这辆公交的刹车
And right now, he is cutting the brakes on this bus
而车上载满了可爱的小蜗牛
full of adorable baby snails
请问  新闻机
Excuse me, Newsbot
如何评价你犯下的罪
Care to comment on your crimes?
事情不是你看来的那样
This isn't what it looks like
看来你已经没新闻了
It looks like you ran out of news
所以你就自己闹事了
so you made your own
我
I--
究竟谁先谁后
So, which came first?
先有新闻报道  还是先有记者
The news story or the reporter?
新  新闻
N-news
记  记者
R-reporter
老太太
Old ladies
船只爆炸
Exploding boats--
我的脸
My face
更多情况  我们采访一下路人
For more, let's go to our man on the street
新闻机
Newsbot
报道
Report
爆炸
Explode
恭喜你  帕奇
Congratulations, Perch
看来你又被雇用了
Looks like you are un-fired
万岁
Hooray
你成功了
You did it
新闻头发还给你
Here's your news hair back
最新消息
This just in
消防员宝宝
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
小蜗
Gary
Gary?
你在哪  小蜗
Where are you, Gere-bear?
小蜗
Gary
怎么跑到上面去了  你这傻蜗牛
How did you get up there, you silly snail?
来吧
Come on
跳下来
Jump
跳啊跳跳跳
Jumpity-jump-jump-jump
按下求救
如遇宠物困在树上  就拉下来
"In case of pet in tree, pull down"
好吧
All right
有谁呼叫消防员的到来
Did someone call the fire department?
让一让  民众
Step aside, citizen
梯子
Ladder
急救箱
First aid
毯子
Blanket
大家快一点
Let's hustle, people
快
Hustle
好
Okay
我来了
Here I come
好
Yeah
你现在安全了  孩子
You're safe now, sonny
快好了
Almost there
谢谢你救了我的小蜗
Thank you for rescuing my little Gare bear
拉里
Hey, Larry
我想当消防员
I'd like to be a firefighter
可以吗  拜托
Can I be one, please?
可不可以
Can I please?
抱歉  海绵宝宝
Sorry, SpongeBob
职位目前没有空缺
There are no openings at this time
我的头骨好像碎了
I think I shattered my skeleton
又来了
Again
虽然我可能会后悔
I may regret this
但是看来职位确实有了空缺
but it looks like we do have an opening
消防站再见吧
See you at the firehouse, I guess
第二天
消防局
你没事吧  海绵宝宝
You okay there, SpongeBob?
啊对
Oh, yeah
前来报到
Reporting for duty
我把我家斑点蜗带来了
I brought my own snail-mation
好吧
Okay
欢迎来到裤头村志愿消防站
Well, welcome to
the Bikini Bottom Volunteer Fire Department
好耶
Oh, yeah
火在哪里
Where's the fire?
我要灭火
I'm gonna fight it
在哪
Where is it?
哪
Where?
对
Yep
我后悔了
I'm regretting it
这里存放的是灭火用的消防水管
Here we keep the hoses that extinguish the fires
水管确实灭了我的渴
Well, they sure extinguished my thirst
上楼
Upstairs
这里是寝室  消防间隙就在这休息
This is the bunk room where we rest up between fires
我可以挑床位吗
Should I pick a bunk?
不行  太软
No, too soft
太硬
Too hard
太芭蕾舞裙
Tutu?
太不平了
Too lumpy
派大星
Patrick
我要烈火了
I'm gonna start fires
是灭火
Put out fires
咱要灭火才对
We put out fires
你说了算
If you say so
菜鸟  认识一下你的志愿同事
Rookie, meet your fellow volunteer
我可高兴了
Charmed, I'm sure
荣幸之至
My pleasure
你有点眼熟
You look familiar
那是什么
What's that?
第一场火灾
The First Fire?
这是史上第一场火灾吗
Is this the first fire in the history of forever?
不对
No
这是我们第一次接到的消防火灾任务
It's the first fire we ever got called to
我们留着它做纪念
We keep it as a memento
消防滑杆
Fire poles
我们可以滑滑杆吗
Can we slide down the poles?
先慢着  菜鸟们
Hold on there, greenhorns
你们得先学习要用哪一个
You need to learn which one to use
这根杆通往消防船
This is the pole to the fire boat
这根杆通往厨房
This one's to the kitchen
好滑啊
It's slippery
上面涂了黄油
It's buttered
这根杆通往卫生间
This pole goes to the bathroom
就滑这根了
That's my ride
这根杆通向哪呢
Where does this pole go?
那根是神秘滑杆
That one's the mystery pole
每次通向的地方都不一样
It never goes to the same place twice
我就爱神秘
I love a mystery
不行
No
等等
Wait
这种疯玩意要怎么停啊
How do you stop this crazy thing?
踩刹车啊
Hit the brakes
不要
No
你还爱神秘吗
Do you still love a mystery?
最近几天不怎么爱了
Not so much these days
好了
All right
列队
Line up
章鱼哥
Squidward
你也来做志愿吗
You volunteered too?
不是我
Not me
是蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
法院强制他来志愿
He was court-mandated for this
他却派我来冒名顶替
but sent me in his stead
我是代理的
I'm a proxy
嗨  代理的
Hi, proxy
我是盒子的
I'm boxy
我是媚气的
I'm foxy
那我就是逃避的
Well, then I'm an escapee
好了
All right
都听好
Listen up
这里是训练区
This is the training area
你们三个之所以来志愿
The reason why there are three of you
是因为一个助步器老头
is because one Old Man Walker
顶三个优良壮丁
is worth three good men
不过我找不到三个优良壮丁
And I couldn't find three good men
就找了你们
so I got you
你们的训练现在开始
Your training starts now
但愿能在某个时刻结束
And hopefully ends at some point
首先是  消防水管技能
First up, fire hose skills
烈火营救
救命
Help
着火了
Fire
谁来救救我的宝宝
Someone save my baby
我们来救你的宝宝
We'll save your baby
小心一点  海绵宝宝
Careful, SpongeBob
慢慢来
Slowly
救救我的宝宝
Save my baby
妈妈
Mama
就听她的
What she said
我救下了宝宝  长官
I saved the baby, chief
那宝宝的妈妈呢
And what about the mother?
宝  宝宝的妈妈
The-the mother?
妈妈
The mother
恭喜大家
Congratulations, men
成功通过训练
You passed your training
好耶
Yeah
灭了我吧
Kill me now
你们都是志愿消防员了
You're all volunteer firefighters
万岁
Huzzah
抱歉  章鱼哥
Sorry, Squidward
我们消防头盔跟对讲机都没了
We're out of fire helmets and walkie talkies
可是
But, um
这是我们上次派对剩的东西
Here's some stuff left over from our last party
又是宠物困在树上吗
Another pet in a tree?
我倒不如去做更好的事
I've got better things to do
比如睡觉
Like sleep
大家动作快
Look alive, men
你们的第一项任务来了
You've got your very first assignment
是点点
It's Spot
它困在树上了
He's stuck in the tree
我胡思乱想什么
What was I thinking?
是海绵宝宝
It's SpongeBob
那没事了
Never mind
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to bother you
就让它待树上得了
He can stay in the tree
让一让  民众
Step aside, citizen
梯子
Ladder
急救箱
First aid
毯子
Blanket
大家快一点
Hustle, people
消防员海绵宝宝呼叫拉里长官
Yeah, this is firefighter SpongeBob to Chief Larry
救援对象吐了派大星一身
The rescue subject
just regurgitated all over Patrick
章鱼哥也被吐到了
Squidward got hurled on too
继续加油干
Keep up the good work
快来吧
Come on, boy
跳
Jump
斑点蜗好样的
Good snail-mation
你们听见没
Do you hear that?
附近起火了
There's a fire somewhere
是真正的火灾
A real fire
快
Hustle
章鱼哥
Squidward
消防警报坏了
The siren is broken
你能不能
Could you, uh
开船看路  白痴
Watch where you're going, bozo
消防站起火了
A fire house on fire
这种讽刺可太劣质了
Talk about your cheap irony
救命
Help
第一场火灾出逃了
The First Fire escaped
救命啊
Save me
好
Okay
跳
Jump
真是劣质
Well, that was a rip off
好了  大伙
Okay, men
使出消防水管技能
Fire hose skills
珍珍的妈啊
Mother of Pearl
放心  你得救了
Don't worry, you're saved
要知道
You know--
谁需要三个优良壮丁
Did somebody need three good men?
你们坚持住  小子们
Now, hold on in there, you kids
我早就说过
Didn't I tell ya
助步器老头顶三个优良壮丁
Old Man Walker is worth three good men?
海绵宝宝呢
Where's SpongeBob?
好
Yes
我救到火了
I saved it
我救到了第一场火灾
I saved the First Fire
不知道能不能找点更安全的志愿来做
I wonder if I can volunteer for something safer
医疗实验
Medical experiments
听着就不错
That sounds good
那你今天运气不错
This is your lucky day
我也是个志愿医生
I'm also a volunteer doctor